#### Partha Pratim Ray

C/O, Ranajit Kumar Ray, Netaji Road, By Lane 2, Newtown, Cooch Behar, WB 736101, India Date of Birth: 9th February, 1986, Mobile: +917908402850

Email: parthapratimray1986@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/partha-pratim-ray-9a6491216

GitHub: https://github.com/ParthaPRay

 $Google\ Scholar:\ https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=ioplfagAAAAJ$ 

#### Summary

An accomplished Assistant Professor with experience in research and development, focusing on Generative AI and IoT, with a keen interest in Large Language Models (LLM). Distinguished as one of the top 2% scientists by Stanford University (2020 - 2023), published over 105 journal articles, 29 conference papers, 2 book chapters, and authored 7 books. Filed 7 national patents, with extensive collaborative experience with international organizations. Active volunteer in IEEE CTSoC and IEEE DewCom STC, contributing to both academic and industry advancements in AI and IoT. Contributed as mentor and collaborated in many projects.

#### Skills

Generative AI: RAG, Hugging Face, Transformer, Vector database, AutoGen, MLOps, Langchain, Chroma, Autonomous AI Agent, LLM

Machine Learning: Python, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Streamlit, Regression, Decision Tree, SVM, Naive Bayes, kNN, K-Means, Dimensionality Reduction Algorithms, Gradient Boosting Algorithms

IoT Tools: ATMEL, Espressif, ARM Cortex-A72 v8, Arduio IDE, Thonny Python IDE, PubNub, Johnny-Five, Sensors, Actuators, MQTT, GPIO, Bluetooth, WiFi, nRF24L01 2.4GHz, GSM, RF 433MHz, Serial, LoRa, I2C, UART, SPI, ThingSpeak, ThingSpoard, ThingWorx, Arduino Cloud, Carritos, Plotly

Research & Publication: Literature Review, Literature Survey, Systematic Analysis, Meta Analysis, SWOT Analysis, Research Article, Latex

# Experience

## Sikkim University (Central University)

July, 2012 - Till Date

Assistant Professor

- Facilitated student learning as a researcher, providing guidance and mentorship.
- $\bullet$  Led the consultancy for the establishment of Intel IoT Center.
- $\bullet\,$  Ensured successful implementation and strategic development.
- Provided key inputs in policy making and entrepreneurship cell monitoring.

# Surendra Institute of Engineering and Management $Assistant\ Professor$

January, 2012 - June, 2012

• Dispensed as a researcher and guided students towards learning.

# Education

## Sikkim University, PhD

Pursuing

Major: AI integration with IoT

West Bengal University of Technology, M.Tech.

November, 2011

Major: Embedded Systems (9.60 DGPA)

West Bengal University of Technology, B.Tech.

August, 2008

Major: Computer Science and Engineering (8.15 DGPA)

#### Awards

- $\bullet$  Earned recognized as Top 2% Scientists by the Stanford University during 2020 2023.
- $\bullet\,$  Secured the "IEI Young Engineers Award 2019-20" in 2020.
- Awarded the "Emerald Literati Awards" in 2019.
- Achieved the "Young Scientist" award in 2017.
- Bestowed with the "Bharat Vikas Award" award in 2017.
- Achieved "Academic Excellence Awards" award in 2017.
- $\bullet\,$  Attained the "Young Achiever Award" award in 2018.
- Selected for the Science Academies' Summer Research Fellowship Programme in 2013.
- Awarded a Post Graduate Scholarship during 2009 2011.